<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>dporras.io.gt</title><link>https://dporras.io.gt/</link><description>Recent content on dporras.io.gt</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 22:15:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dporras.io.gt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Review: Practical DevSecOps CDP</title><link>https://dporras.io.gt/posts/cdp-review/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 21:20:04 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://dporras.io.gt/posts/cdp-review/</guid><description>TL;DR Won&amp;rsquo;t make you an expert, but gives very good base Believe them when they say Practical, be ready to actually DO stuff by yourself. Short curse, concise, very informative Teaches how to transform a regular CI/CD pipeline into a production ready DevSecOps* pipeline Good for beginners in DevOps, but at least you have some IT background They mention commercial products, but the course is focused on open source tools. Context During early 2020 (the good old days :cowboy: ) I moved from my role as pentester to be an Application security dude at company XYZ.</description></item><item><title>Review: Cloud DevOps Engineer Nanodegree</title><link>https://dporras.io.gt/posts/review_udacity_devops_nd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 18:00:45 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://dporras.io.gt/posts/review_udacity_devops_nd/</guid><description>On March 15th Udacity launched a promotion aimed to help people affected by the pandemic. (yup! the Covid-19 thing I&amp;rsquo;m tired of).
This was about getting a completely free one month access (30 days) to any of their programs. I took advantage and gave it a try. I enrolled in the DevOps nanodegree and here are my thoughts.
TL;DR The program is worth it if you have basic knowledge of cloud and docker containers.</description></item><item><title>Kernel Adventures</title><link>https://dporras.io.gt/posts/kernel/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 22:15:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dporras.io.gt/posts/kernel/</guid><description>Tile image source: https://static.lwn.net/images/pdf/LDD3/ch01.pdf
How much about linux kernel can be learned in 30 days? Let&amp;rsquo;s find out.
Day 1: CH1: An introduction to device drivers &amp;ldquo;The Linux kernel remains a large and complex body of code, however, and would-be kernel hackers need an entry point where they can approach the code without being overwhelmed by com- plexity. Often, device drivers provide that gateway&amp;rdquo;
Take aways:
The kernel functionality can be roughly classified as: Process management Memory management Filesystems Device control Networking Device drivers could be of mainly 3 types (There are other more specialized types): Char modules Block modules Network modules In linux a module is a hot-pluggable piece of object code.</description></item></channel></rss>