<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on The Art of hacking - blog</title><link>http://aleph.theartofhacking.club/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on The Art of hacking - blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 23:07:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://aleph.theartofhacking.club/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Review: Practical DevSecOps CDP</title><link>http://aleph.theartofhacking.club/posts/cdp-review/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 21:20:04 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://aleph.theartofhacking.club/posts/cdp-review/</guid><description>TL;DR Won&amp;rsquo;t make you an expert, but gives very good base Believe them when they say Practical, be ready to actually DO stuff by yourself. Short curse, concise, very informative Teaches how to transform a regular CI/CD pipeline into a production ready DevSecOps* pipeline Good for beginners in DevOps, but at least you have some IT background They mention commercial products, but the course is focused on open source tools. Context During early 2020 (the good old days :cowboy: ) I moved from my role as pentester to be an Application security dude at company XYZ.</description></item><item><title>Review: Cloud DevOps Engineer Nanodegree</title><link>http://aleph.theartofhacking.club/posts/review_udacity_devops_nd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 18:00:45 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://aleph.theartofhacking.club/posts/review_udacity_devops_nd/</guid><description>On March 15th Udacity launched a promotion aimed to help people affected by the pandemic. (yup! the Covid-19 thing I&amp;rsquo;m tired of).
This was about getting a completely free one month access (30 days) to any of their programs. I took advantage and gave it a try. I enrolled in the DevOps nanodegree and here are my thoughts.
TL;DR The program is worth it if you have basic knowledge of cloud and docker containers.</description></item><item><title>Kage bunshin no jutsu: clone(2)</title><link>http://aleph.theartofhacking.club/posts/clone2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 23:07:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://aleph.theartofhacking.club/posts/clone2/</guid><description>This entry talks about the clone(2) system call and the corresponding libc thin wrapper. I talk about some issues I found whle using the syscall to solve Advent - day 2.
TL;DR Process creation in linux Namespaces in linux: CLONE_NEW*, CLONE_NEWNS, user namespaces. Linux capabilities. CAP_SYS_ADMIN Practical use of the namespaces API: clone(2) My full solutions are available here: https://github.com/dporr/kernel_syscalls/tree/master/02-clone It all starts with fork(2): https://man7.org/tlpi/download/TLPI-24-Process_Creation.pdf
The most basic way of creating a new process in linux is using the fork(2) sycall.</description></item><item><title>Kernel Adventures</title><link>http://aleph.theartofhacking.club/posts/kernel/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 22:15:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://aleph.theartofhacking.club/posts/kernel/</guid><description>Tile image source: https://static.lwn.net/images/pdf/LDD3/ch01.pdf
How much about linux kernel can be learned in 30 days? Let&amp;rsquo;s find out.
The content for the series comes mainly from 2 resources used in no particualr order.
Linux Device Drivers, Third Edition. Freely available here https://lwn.net/Kernel/LDD3/ Hamburg&amp;rsquo;s university - Advent(2) - https://osg.tuhh.de/Advent/
Each day I wil publish a list of lessons learned from the linked material, any additional resources I used and things that were particularly interesting while doing the practical parts.</description></item></channel></rss>